hello I'm your host David Barnard and my
guest today is Greg Stewart CEO at
ladder a fitness app dedicated to
providing the world's best strength
training plan from the world's best
coaches every single day on the podcast
I talk with Greg about profitably
scaling Tik Tok ads price optimization
and what the team learn from burning
hundreds of thousands of dollars on
Instagram ads hey Greg thanks so much
for joining me on the podcast today
thanks for for having me we're happy
customer so happy to be here and doing
this with you awesome so I'm super
excited to talk through your growth
strategy because you've unlocked some
things I think a lot of folks have
struggled on and I think you've got a
lot of great knowledge and experience to
share but let's get it off with what is
Ladder because I think that's going to
really help kind of inform how you
approach your growth strategy so what is
lad ladder is an app for strength
training for people who are serious
about Fitness we make it really easy to
plan and maintain a progressive strength
training routine cool so how long have
you been at it what's kind of the
journey been so far from like a product
company standpoint yeah we launched the
product in the middle of covid in July
2021 which was an interesting time to be
launching a fitness app for sure wow was
that good not as people would expect we
locked the strategy down really in Q4
2018 and q1 2019 so before
covid was part of our everyday lives and
our Focus for our first phase for the
product was somebody going to the gym so
this is somebody who is already working
out going to the gym for most of their
workouts and looking for an easier way
to plan their workouts just tired
thinking about what to do or searching
for content and so we are hyper focused
on the 65 million Americans at the gym
which we thought was a underserved
segment from a technology persp
perspective we were that user you are
that user and our view that it was
mostly casual Fitness and cardio that
had the attention of innovators and of
venture capital so we saw an opportunity
and fortunately unfortunately depending
on what time period you look at it co
became part of our everyday life and we
had a plan to launch and we did and had
to be really creative to be relevant to
a user who is getting bombarded by all
kinds of new products at that moment and
some somebody who was at home in their
house with no equipment versus a full
gym that they were used to trading with
so I had to just be really creative to
figure out how to stand out in that
moment yeah so how did that early user
acquisition go like what were some of
the ways you got that initial traction
even though you weren't maybe the best
product Market fit for the time period
you launched in you did start promoting
the app and get some early traction what
did that look like yeah well we had to
be relevant for at home so we had to be
conscious of that when we were thinking
about about our content and working with
our launch coaches and our coach
Partners at the time now most of them
are full-time teammates but at the time
they were partners and these coaches had
micro audiences on mostly Instagram so
call it 10 to 50,000 followers and had a
direct line into consumers who were
looking for help in that moment in time
how to stay interested and consistent
when their whole have been flipped
upside down based on their environment
changing so we got pretty crafty at
helping our coaches tell the right story
to their audiences about ladder about
their program on ladder the positioning
talking to the right users and that was
really helpful in going zero to one like
we went zero to a million bucks of AR
and the focus wasn't Revenue but more so
on product iteration and using that
initial cohort of members to make sure
that one the thesis was right and there
was a path to validating product Market
fit but two that we just had got the
product experience right or getting a
feel for where we had to improve it
before really pushing harder what did
that look like you say Partners so when
you were partnering with an influencer
in that early stage you know sounds like
it's evolved over time but in that early
stage how did you form those
Partnerships and you said there were
micro influencers so it sounds like they
didn't have a huge following themselves
at the time what did that partnership
look like and did you get a lot of
traction even from those smaller
audiences that those influencers had and
varying levels of AUD micro meaning not
millions of followers they're not
household names but 15 to 50 to 100,000
followers which was an exciting basket
because these folks were following those
coaches for Fitness content these were
coaches in the strength training space
really reputable so they had a loyal
hyper relevant following we didn't need
huge following to tell the right story
to get people into the app relevant
hyper intent like the best way to do
influencers is find that most relevant
with like they can drive that super high
intent user exactly and if Co did help
at that moment is we could get on the
phone with a lot of coaches that
probably should not have been talking to
a company at that stage we were very
early we had no users and we were
pitching on Google slides and we treated
them with respect and we would put
together custom PowerPoint decks with
their face and brand and name and really
tell a story to the coach which actually
we learned was standing out versus other
companies that were constantly
bombarding them with different offers so
we made it in that first moment all
about them and how we thought about the
coach and how important that role was to
even the early endings of the business
that led to some really exciting coach
partners that most of them are still
with us today I think a lot of folks try
and figure out influencer marketing and
fail so as much as you're open to
sharing how those were even structured
was there some kind of like affiliate
was it a per post fee or how did you
even structure those micro influencer
campaigns we set it up where we wanted
perfect alignment with these coaches and
so the first phase at that point it was
splitting every dollar after the Apple
commission and we knew that wasn't a
long-term path but we wanted to show
these coaches that we weren't just here
to be a platform partner we're going to
invest heavily upfront and we're not
thinking about this as a Marketplace our
customer from the beginning is the
consumer so we're looking for coaches
who want to work with us to nail the
consumer experience not who are looking
for a coach tools business to partner
with just to serve the audience that
they had acquired so a really F
partnership where we end did all the up
for investment shot all the content flew
them to Austin in the middle of covid
which had all kinds of protocols and Co
testing kits at our studio and just a
nightmare from Logistics perspective but
we got it done thankfully and it was
exciting to have a great group of
coaches to launch with at that moment
yeah so the latter app is fairly unique
in the fitness space and correct me if
I'm wrong exactly how it works but I've
used it a couple times when you open the
app you actually pick a coach and
there's like a lot of different coaching
options with different styles of
workouts with different equipment or no
equipment and those kind of things so
did you share the revenue based on who
selected them as a coach and retained as
a coach or did you use like affiliate
codes or something else to track the
revenue in order to share it with the
influencers we had unique and still do
UTM on their link and bio in Instagram
so we could see everything that was
coming in through that link they go to a
landing page that is all about that
coach because at that point on Instagram
they' made a decision to be in this
coaches program or team as we call them
so the experience is tightly correlated
if you're going down that path where you
click out and it's the coach that you've
just come from on Instagram and that's
happening before you go into the app so
that UTM led us track where it was
coming from and we still have that same
infrastructure in link and bio for all
of our coaches the partnership and the
way we work with coaches has changed but
that kind of cor infrastructure is still
in place interesting so then were you
actually doing like web onboarding and
even web pay walls or were you doing
minimal onboarding and then sending them
to the app it depends on where you come
from and this is after a whole bunch of
iteration but for the first year and a
half most of our triers were coming from
our coaches and we were helping them and
creating the content and the positioning
points and obviously the landing page
and all of the collateral they would
need to be effective to get folks into
the app and they were talking about
their program or their team in ladder
and if you're going down that path
you've already made a choice on the
coach that you're looking to train with
we need to get you into the app into
that team as quickly as possible and so
if you're coming through coach marketing
typically Linkin bio you're going to go
to One landing page which is just really
quick high level educating on what the
product is what the experience is a
little bit on the coach what type of
training style equipment that you need
and then you're going right into the app
if you come from any other source for
the most part or any of our channels who
are investing in growth you're going
through a web onboarding where we're
asking about 15 questions about your
Fitness preferences so we're asking you
how many days a week you work out how
many days a week you lift weights what
training Styles you gravitate towards
what equipment you want to train with
where are you working out what are your
goals and we use those questions to
recommend a team again those are our
programs but we call them team at the
end of that quiz and at the end of that
quiz they've got three programs that are
directly tied to the answers that they
just gave us and you can think about our
coaches almost like The Avengers each
one represents unique trading Styles and
we're not looking for thousands of
coaches and really the same programming
style across all over coaches we're
looking for really exciting Variety in
programming and having that be
represented by the coach and that web
quiz has actually been an amazing tool
for us we've had a million people go
through it over the last year and a half
and it gives us a really clear glimpse
into what the market is looking for
versus what we have represented in our
coach roster and so like a simple
example is we saw about a third of our
leads every day were saying they wanted
traditional bodybuilding and at that
moment it was mostly women who were
coming through our funnel and saying
that and we didn't have a traditional
bodybuilding program so the conversion
rate for that user versus someone who
didn't say they wanted bodybuilding was
half so we could really clearly
underwrite what the demand would look
like how big this team would be very
quickly before we even had a
conversation about who a great coach
partner would be and once we lock that
in we pick the programming style then we
go out and we do hyper targeted
recruiting of the r coach partner to
join us to fill that modality so we've
shifted from a world where we were
completely dependent on coaches having
an audience to where we know what's
coming in every day and can be really
smart about putting in the right
programming style that's clearly missing
from our product Suite but has real
consistent demand that's coming through
our funnel we had the same thing happen
on mail bodybuilding and we launched a
male bodybuilding team earlier this year
those were our last two launches and
they're some of our fastest growing most
popular programs and they're all
informed by that quiz a lot of people
try influencer marketing and they think
oh well if Kim Kardashian posted about
my app that would just blow us up but
you kind of win the opposite approach of
like you're finding folks who don't who
have decent followings but like you said
hyper targeted followings and then help
them build that up over time versus the
inverse where you just try and get the
biggest influencer regardless of the
intent the fit with your product and
stuff like that so it's something I
think more folks should explore as an
opportunity you know talked with several
developers now about affiliate marketing
and it's essentially what you're doing
but then eventually you kind of
transition that to them becoming part of
the team which is really cool and we
learned like this wasn't a Marketplace
and it wasn't a tools for coaches
platform it wasn't a Creator platform
this is a consumer business from the
start and we learned the importance over
time of having the right coach partners
that were excellent from a workout
programming coaching perspective in and
great Partners in terms of working with
our team and we're excited to be part of
a company at this stage and really grow
something that was way more impactful
long run than just finding folks with
big audiences in fact some of the
programs that are no longer on the
platform they were some of our biggest
audiences but maybe we overweighted that
versus The Importance of Being a great
coach and a great teammate to the
business so in those early stages were
there any other organic channels or any
other of launch techniques or
experimentation that you did in that
early stage or was it primarily driven
through this like just organic have the
coaches post kind of thing that first
phas it was all organic Instagram we did
some creative things at a moment in time
again we were launching in Co this is a
strength training app if you remember
that moment it was impossible to get any
sort of equipment I tried yeah there was
an article in the Walsh Journal I
remember it I think it was on the cover
and it was talking about the Kettlebell
King of New York York and this guy was
buying kettlebell inventory from defunk
gyms commercial gyms in New York and he
was taking those and selling them door
too to folks in Manhattan and charging
two to three times what they were worth
of because you couldn't get them
anywhere and none of these equipment
manufacturers were really set up to be
direct to Consumer they were all B2B to
see so we had a moment where we
scrambled to figure out how do we lock
down some equipment so we removed that
as a block for these potential trailers
potential users and we found a partner
after a whole bunch of work in the
hardest moment to find equipment and we
bought like $50,000 worth of kettle
bells and dumbbells and this is like we
were very early with very little money
but we use that to create a Shopify shop
that sold this equipment but you
couldn't get access to the equipment
unless you started a trial in our app
and so you got access to the link inside
of the app and our coaches would use
that to say hey everybody's looking for
kettle bells this is an amazing
experience I'm going to coach you all
the way through it but if you just get
in the app and start a trial you're
gonna get access to a store that
actually has it in stock and that just
gave them a really relevant bit of
content to go out to their audience at a
moment in time where you just couldn't
get it you couldn't get it so we had to
do some creative things to stand out at
that particular moment that is such an
awesome like Scrappy read the market
figure out what's going to get you
attention thing I mean I love hearing
these kind of Scrappy stories and that's
what it's all about right it's getting
attention you need attention so how are
you going to get attention Kim
Kardashian posting yeah she's got 100
million followers but they're not as
relevant okay micro influencers well
what's a story that they can tell that's
super compelling that's going to get you
a ton of attention buying equipment like
that such a cool Scrappy story so I
think I heard you say that just on that
organic strategy partnering with coaches
that got you to a million dollars in ARR
it did pretty pretty quickly and it was
an entire motion of the team to help
support these coaches and we're
iterating on the Frog experience too to
make it really efficient for a Trier
coming in to experience the product
there was no credit card collected
upfront that's still true today because
we were competing on product and the
noise in the Market at that time was
very loud everybody was building a
fitness app and the consumer was
open-minded but getting bombarded from
offers and brand and some that they
heard of some that they had not heard of
after you hit that million dollars in
ARR what was the next phase of growth
what were you thinking about did you try
meta ads Google ads what did you try
next to kind of unlock that next level
of growth the first two years were
hardcore product iteration and just
making sure again the thesis was right
that the core delivery of the workout
experience was right and then we built
an entire set of tools for our coaches
and our team to power all of this a
product called Apollo which I think is
the best software for coaches but it's
just used for our team and constantly
getting better and better but it it
Powers everything that we do so for the
first couple years mostly organic
Instagram and just helping our coach
exra we would launch new programs and
teams which would be new audiences that
we would help those coaches extract
Travers from we rais a little bit of C
capital or C+ capital in mid
2021 and we did what we thought every
consumer should do or you're told to do
and we started putting money into
Facebook paid and that was an utter
disaster and we got just absolutely
slaughtered in that experience we
learned a lot but it was macro and micro
challenges the macro challenges where
you had everybody in Fitness who were
chasing the consumer at the same time
and most of those Brands had much bigger
budgets and a lot more experience and
then it was also right after iOS 14 came
out so everybody was upside down from a
acquisition and attribution perspective
which made even talking to agencies very
difficult because everybody was in chaos
and then from a micro perspective we
learned a lot about our activation
process our price point we talked about
our early users were mostly coming from
a coach and we talk to these people all
the time we learned that they were
following that coach and they were
making a decision to go into the app to
train with that coach but if you were
somebody that was coming off a Facebook
ad you might be the right user
somebody's working out and looking for a
solution like this but they had no
context of any of our coaches or
programming Styles so we had to be
really good at getting them into the
right program and the right workout as
quickly as possible or they wouldn't
give us a shot and there was no way we
could get the unit economics to work and
so that first phase we didn't have
anything set up that was different than
our influencer coach path and users came
in and they were just confused they
didn't know where to go and they were
doing all the wrong things and we
couldn't get people through through the
workout we learned pretty quickly that
we had to think from a product
perspective a lot harder and seriously
about activation in a user who is maybe
the right user but knows nothing other
than the ad or the content that they
just saw to get them into the app so
that was a huge learning and then we
talked to those that did get into the
app then didn't pay us which was most we
talked to them and I probably had a
hundred conversations with folks just
learning and we learned at those
conversation that our price point was
totally out of whack and when we
launched we were $60 a month and that's
very expensive and the reason it was $60
a month was because the product had a
component that gave you onetoone chat
with the coach and it was never meant to
be chatting with a friend type
experience but it was designed almost
like an OnStar button where you had a
specific question question or an injury
and you needed a modification to a
movement or you didn't have equipment
you would get within a reasonable amount
of time an answer from the coach and so
that's an expensive feature to maintain
and we built software to make it as easy
as possible but we priced the product
around that in the first phase and we
weren't sure how important it was to the
experience well we learned from those
leads we acquired from Facebook that
they actually had no interest in
chatting with the coach they wanted high
quality workout programming they wanted
an easy experience to know exactly what
to do every day but they didn't want to
pay 60 bucks a month you know they're
looking at Netflix at the time or
Spotify and were two three 4X what
they're paying for every other content
subscription and the price value
equation was just completely out of
whack and that became very very clear to
us and so all those things together were
just like three months of frustration
where we learned a bunch but it just
wasn't a good use of investor capital
and we paused spending and put our heads
down and committed to overhauling
monetization strategy price point how we
packaged and really nailing the
activation experience for somebody
coming in that just doesn't know
anything about ladder other than the
sound bite they just got before they
came into the app and that was pretty
much all the entire team's Focus all my
focus Q4 of 2021 and launched all that
the beginning of the year January is our
super Super Bowl our user tends to be
someone who's already working out but
January is the most open-minded any
consumer is in Fitness open to trying
new things at that moment in time we
geared up to have everything ready to go
in January 2022 and it was exciting for
us like we weren't spending on growth
but we had acquired a for us a decent
Siz database of leads and we had a new
price point and new packaging and new
positioning and we went out to that
group and acquired a whole bunch of
folks that had said no the first time
and so we felt a lot lot more confident
in the foundation of the product the
trial experience the price point to
really start thinking about investing in
growth again and growing Beyond just the
audiences that our coaches had acquired
man there's like 10 questions I want to
ask you packed into all of that first of
all I don't think it was a bad use of
investor money because spending whatever
you did probably tens if not hundreds of
thousands of dollars taught you the
lessons that you needed to go into
hibernation mode for Q4 where you
weren't spending on acquisition to
retool everything and so I think people
too often expect to just turn on ads and
it's just going to work but you took the
right lessons from that wasn't oh we
just need to get more efficient with our
ads oh we need more adte oh we need a
different MMP oh we need this we need
that it's like no we need a better
product 100% and our DNA is product and
marketing not Performance Marketing at
the time so our default was what can we
do in the experience what can we do in
telling the right story to the right
person not how can we out optimize this
in Facebook ads but no it was a learning
experience in the moment it felt like a
gut punch every day coming into work and
just looking at conversion rates and
just money being lit on fire in a moment
that was just hard but looking back it
was the exact thing that needed to
happen to make it really clear what to
focus on to set us up for much more
success longer term than that moment in
sry yeah the other really interesting
thing you said in there was that you
originally were priced at $60 a month
which yeah it does it sounds crazy like
I don't know many apps are just 60 bucks
a month but you got to a million dollars
in ARR so the price wasn't an issue like
you were actually delivering that level
of value but you were delivering that
level of value for people who are really
bought into those specific coaches but
then the point was you can't scale like
that and I've heard a lot of talk about
this in the industry like Eric sufur
talked about this you find this initial
product Market fit with an organic
Channel or some like kind of narrow
channel and you're like oh KAC is
amazing like monetization is going
through the roof and then you try and
expand that audience out and you don't
get those same willingness to pay you
don't get that same engagement you don't
get the same level of intent was it
clear that you did have to change
everything and lower the price I mean
did you try or was there a thought maybe
we could scale with more influencers or
what was the thought process that led
you to lower the price versus trying to
find the right audiences who were
willing to pay that high of a price we
went through a really really deep
exercise extracting as much information
from our users our database our members
people who didn't pay us to understand
the price value equation for them and we
weren't guessing when we launched at 60
bucks I have like this spreadsheet that
was like my trying angulation of Super
One toone Solutions maybe high
performance training train something
very specific all the way down to
influencer PDFs and we had a combination
of both we had the one and component
which gave me a little bit of confidence
the price higher and so your point
before that made sense for that user
because they're vieing these coaches as
Heroes and they are but like they knew
that before they got into the app so to
pay 60 bucks a month to chat with your
hero is really cheap
right and so the value that they got out
of it was high that was just a much
smaller use case than the market that we
were going after and really the market
that would be required to go build a
business that was sustainable over time
on the influencer side we just never
thought about ourselves maybe it changes
long long term as a tools for business
and what I learned on launching coaches
which was really exciting but the most
exciting moment is the first couple
weeks because you're telling a fresh
story to that coach's audience maybe
they had an offering maybe they didn't
and you're going to get a whole bunch of
excitement and people into the app but
it goes down over time and the reason
for that is it was very hard to help
them build their followings at Instagram
faster than the value that we were
extracting from it so it became clear
that this was a growth hack the one that
was great for a moment in time but it
wasn't a growth engine that was
sustainable it didn't go up it went down
down over time and so that was just a
really clear lesson to us on that
audience saturation right so as a
percentage of Their audience even if you
could increase Their audience slowly you
weren't increasing the audience fast
enough to offset the saturation of
whatever audience they did have before
so the equation then looked like okay we
could get a thousand more coaches but
for all that effort maybe there's a
better way so then what was the thought
process how did you decide on a new
price and kind of a new model to kind of
swap in this new growth engine that you
felt was more sustainable and Powerful
in the long run we actually used reforge
content for this which was a game
changer in the moment because I didn't
want to guess and time was not infinite
in terms of Runway versus proving
something out and they had just really
great content about how to think about
monetization strategy and how to extract
the right pieces of information from
cohorts of users whether those were
paying subscribers or those that decided
not to pay you through trial and they
had some analysis in there and this type
of work is fun for me I love this type
of work that was the van West Andor
pricing analysis where one of the
questions we asked and we had 500
responses to this and we asked all those
segments at what price point is ladder
so expensive that you never buy it at
what price point is Ladder expensive but
you still consider purchasing it at what
point is L price point is Ladder a good
deal and at what price point is it so
cheap that question the quality of the
product and out of that there's a
formula that spits out an optimal price
point range and the game was slicing it
by all these different cohorts so those
that came from a coach those that came
from Facebook ad those that cared about
different objectives from a training
perspective or modality and really
triangulating around who we thought our
core user was and the very clear lesson
was people wanted the workout
programming content high quality stra
train content they didn't want to think
about what to do that was by far the
value prop so planning my workouts not
thinking at all was what these people
were screaming at us that they were
getting from the product and then it
became very clear that they had no
interest in paying for a coach and the
clearing price across all of these
cohorts was 29 bucks and we sliced this
a thousand different ways and I got a
thousand different charts and a thousand
page deck and it just became pretty
clear through all of this work that that
was the right price point for us to
launch with and so when we launched it
it was just Join one team so you're on
that coach's team you can change once
not twice per month if you want to but
it's designed to be in a program and no
onetoone access we have social
experiences you get all that obviously
we have gamification in the app you get
all of that but no personalization in a
much cheaper price point that reflects
that did you do at that time or
subsequently any AB price testing or do
you even offer different cohorts to
different prices like since you know
that somebody coming from an influencer
is actually willing to pay more do you
charge them more or did you just
normalize on 30 it wasn't worth the
complexity of the over like it was so
blatantly obvious that this was the
right price and there was so much work
qualitative and quantitative that went
through this we talked through it as a
team and then I talked through it with
our board it just felt like a very clear
move for us and creating the overhead of
different SKS and trying to get
different price points just didn't make
sense we were trying to prove product
Market fit and that we could grow and
getting the price point to a place where
we could start iterating on growth again
that was the objective not trying to
squeeze every dollar that we could out
of every user coming in so we were
trying for more simple the better get it
right get the offering right learn from
January and the flood of activity then
and then start iterating on growth again
assuming we felt confident that we got
it right we're close enough to right
okay so it's January 202 to people are
excited about New Year's resolutions
how'd it go what was that next lever in
growth January was awesome because we
went to this whole database of people
that said no that we bought off Facebook
but we had a much more compelling price
point that was closer to their price
value equation so January was our most
exciting growth we had had and then we
didn't grow in February and not growing
in consumer and in Fitness in any month
in the first quarter is a death sentence
and that was a very clear like holy
moment for the entire team and for me
and really a forcing function to move
the entire team and we're a small team
you know we're 13 14 people into
focusing on growth and figuring out a
real sustainable Channel motion but
growth Loop that we could rely on for
the next couple of phases as a business
and we didn't have infinite Runway and
we knew we had to prove that we could do
this and it just became the mission of
every team member engineering product
myself to go solve this problem there
was no more important problem at the
time yeah it's amazing what you can
achieve when the whole company is
focused on one thing and those
incentives all lining up to solving that
one problem so what worked and did you
do any other experiments along the way
that failed or what did you land on as
that growth Loop we came up with a frame
framework to figure out a basket of
growth RS to experiment quickly and the
framework essentially was we have to
have a reason to believe that this can
work so not just Pie in the Sky
hopefully it will work but have a real
grounded reason either from our
experience or our advantages or how our
business is built or our team that we
thought there was a path to winning and
we had to test it in our own team I went
through the Facebook experience and I
had an agency and I made all the
mistakes in the world partnering with
the wrong agency partnering with a in
general and I'll never work with a
marketing agency ever again outside of
our team as a consumer business I have
learned and that wasn't my DNA at that
point I have learned that there is no
muscle more important than growth and
that includes investing in growth that
includes the products I have growth that
includes retention so to have those
learnings and to have that dial being
controlled out to the building now makes
no sense whatsoever to me but out of
that framework came a handful of grow
loopes and one of those was SEO we're
creating all of this content I talked to
some really smart people I read a bunch
of books and we felt confident that we
could do it but we learned pretty
quickly that this is a longtail strategy
there was not going to be meaningful
points on the board but we found I I
found some course by going out to people
that I think are smart and hacky and it
was basically validating that this can
work for you and we figured out a
strategy using copy AI to create the
text but it basically was movement
how-to featuring content that we were
creating in the app and we got to page
one on Google for three of these within
60 days and so it was clear that we have
really compelling content there is a
path to winning in this strategy but
it's not going to be fast enough to go
prove what we need to go prove right now
so that failed our validation test even
though it failed that validation of it
being a core pillar is it something that
you've continued to invest in over time
or did you just have to completely set
that aside no we set it aside we'll come
back to it for sure but it just wasn't
going to move the needle and we didn't
have the luxury of just like hoping
certain things would work and diverting
attention we had to have complete focus
on one thing at a time and one of the
growth Loops that was part of that
process was Tik Tock and we obviously
had experience on Instagram now a couple
of years of learning how to be effective
with our coaches to tell the r story to
Their audience and we could see that
that was getting harder and harder over
time forget the paid side even on the
organic side it was just getting harder
to get the same reach as we went and Tik
Tok as consumers we could see that the
consumer was moving to Tik Tok we could
see the growth and the engagement in Tik
Tok and this was two or three years
before that I mean we knew this was
happening we have influencers on our
staff we're talking about these things
on a regular basis and I just started
messing around long before that growth
Lo validation this was 2020 I started
messing around a little bit with one of
our coaches who was super smart and been
with us from the beginning and I said
hey I think this is worth trying and
seeing what we can learn it feels like
our consumer is moving here and we have
some interesting advantages and it
doesn't cost us anything to learn on the
organic side so we spent time together
really dissecting we created a handle
for her as is coach Lauren can
and we started creating content and
dissecting what was working and what was
not working and trying to find
repeatable outcomes on organic views but
we learned pretty quickly that yes the
relevant consumer is here the engagement
was high once we got to a thousand
followers we had link and bio it was
generating some trials as we were going
so there was enough of a path that it
came back into our minds in the first
quarter of 2022 so that was one of them
hey we maybe can do this we've got
strong creative abilities and we've
learned a lot through Instagram and
we've messed around with Tik Tok and we
know that it's possible to get somebody
off Tik Tok into our app and to pay us
we pushed on that and I remember we had
a moment where I took my creative
director now VP of brand and creative
who's been my partner in crime Philip
edel he goes by hedel and I took him to
breakfast and I said like hey man like
do you want to work on Tik Tok with me
and he said yes and I said well good it
was an option like we're going to go
work on Tik Tok he was super excited and
edel is an unbelievably brilliant
creative mind and was head of creative
at Austin FC our MLS team and was there
from launch so just really good at blank
sheet iteration and a really really
incredible mind that can solve problems
and can solve creative problems and we
had a coach that was launching around
that time and we wanted to go figure out
the organic we wanted to figure out can
we create compelling content we did it
with Lauren a little bit can we do it
with somebody else and can we create a
system that works and we started an
account for one of our new coaches who
had zero experience on Tik Tok we were
like hey this will be your account but
we're going to act as you for the first
couple months we're going to take all
your raw video that you've ever created
and these are Fitness influencers so
they have a lot of raw video on their
phone and we're going to see what we can
do and we started creating content with
no new video but we got to 250,000
followers like 45 days later and we're
like all right so like that worked and
like we're generating million plus view
outcomes and we're doing it on a weekly
basis there's something there but it
gave us a really strong understanding of
the creative and how to iterate and the
differences versus Instagram and just
enough confidence to keep going like we
felt like there was a Playbook there was
a Playbook here so it all started with
Organic and that was February March 45
days later we're like all right we've
seen enough to maybe start putting some
dollars to work and seeing what that
turns into and how far off are we and we
had all these scars from our Facebook
experience so there's certainly some
apprehen mention especially for me
there's no one on our team at that point
with a marketing in their title it was
me and elel and I'm taking courses on
Tik Tok Performance Marketing figuring
out what buttons to click I love math I
love Creative so I like the work but
just didn't come from at D which
actually was helpful thinking through
with a completely open mind how to
attack a problem on Tik Tok which is a
new platform and behaved very
differently with a very different use
case than Instagram for the user and we
started putting a little bit of money to
work based on those learnings with Edo
creating and he and I just talking all
day long and very quickly started to
turn into trials and paid members and it
was infinitely more exciting than our
first couple weeks of Facebook it gave
us real conviction to keep learning but
it all started with nailing the organic
and then starting to put some Capital
behind it and iterating on the paid side
so what did that early motion look like
since you started with this new coach
and I imagine you started ramping up
other coaches on Tik Tok around the time
as well would you see what landed
organically and then put money behind it
or did you start creating content
specifically for the ads or did you let
the organic visibility kind of Drive
what you actually put money behind we
tried everything and everything was
documented and we had a thesis and a
reasonably different things would work
but there are a couple of different ways
to spend money on Tik Tok and what we've
learned over time that is that organic
is the best indication of when content
we were creating brand ads featuring
coaches that were winning on Tik Tok but
really using the organic insights the
hooks the messaging the copy the coach
that where the outlier coaches that
started to inform the type of content
that we would create on the brand side
and then we learned spark which is just
wh listing and Tik Tok but taking the
coach's organic content and then turning
that into an ad and pointing that in a
direction that we set and that was also
explosive very very quickly for us and
we worked with Tik Tock the company at
that point who we gotten to know a
couple of folks to figure out how do we
connect ads manager I'm the only guy
pushing buttons in there how do we
connect ads manager to all of these
organic accounts that we're building
with our coaches because we were just
doing codes which was not fast enough
the amount of volume that it takes to
win on Tik Tok is very high so you need
a really high level of volume and speed
of iteration to keep fueling the machine
and so we connected all these accounts
so that I could look every day to see
what was high performing or outlier
organic content related to ladder or
their program and I could turn those
into an ad in seconds and that became a
big piece of our paid acquisition
strategy that would live alongside the
brand strategy so what kind of content
did perform and then the thing I've
always and talking to folks who've tried
Tik Tok ads one of the challenging
things is like turning something that's
engaging as content itself into a call
to action so what did the call to
actions look like and how did you work a
call to action into what looked like
organic content step one which is just
marketing oneone was understanding our
customer and understanding them at a
really really deep level and words that
they use and I've done a lot of work
take well feedback that's come through
us through our own team but also
dissecting the app store we have almost
16,000 reviews in the App Store and I've
taken all that and very manually gone
through and created value propositions
and problem solution statements using
the words that are coming out of our
user mouth and how they were explaining
the product and what they were getting
and so like we really really understand
understand our customer to the point
where I don't think anybody in the world
understands this customer better than we
do and that obviously is then filtered
through any sort of creative but
especially on Tik Tok but for Tik Tok we
had to learn how to create for Tik Tok
on Instagram the motion is very very
different especially on organic on
Instagram you are rewarded for building
up a following and then over time you
spend your time trying to extract value
and trying to monetize that audience
that you've acquired so you build this
million per following and you try to
sell them relevant goods and services
and sometimes those are your products
and sometimes they're a brand Partners
that's working with you as an influencer
so the motion is build up a following
put up great content and constantly
speak to that following Tik Tok is the
exact opposite where most of the content
that's being consumed is through the
foru page and the for you page is Tik
Tok feeding you content that it thinks
you like based on your prior user
Behavior and the content that you were
consuming and where you're stopping and
so it's saying you like startups and you
like subscription and you like baseball
and it's feeding you that back to you
but you have no idea who the creators
are for the most part so most videos
that we learned are an entirely
different audience every time so we had
to spend time with our coaches to
basically unlearn all of the behaviors
that made them successful on Instagram
and they would have Notions of I wore
this in the post yesterday or I haven't
given them behind the scenes in a couple
of weeks and with Tik tok's like it just
doesn't matter you can assume it's a
different Auditorium of people every
video so if it's a new Auditorium of
people there's no preconceived notions
coming in there's no anchoring to what
you did yesterday they're not going to
your profile and consuming it linearly
they're finding you through the for you
page because Tik Tok thinks that your
content is valuable to that user based
on what it knows about that user's
behavior and that just completely
changes how you think about the creative
and the type of creative that you're
building I think what we learned with
our coaches and then we have Tik Tok
creators that are incredible in our team
that are not coaches we learn the
importance of first understanding the
platform and how it's used understanding
the for you page which was just spending
time using the product second was what
is the type of content that worked it's
not high production it's not stuff
that's working on Facebook or Instagram
it's raw and shot with an iPhone and
even editing in Tik Tok made the
difference of it working or not versus
using something that you had created in
Instagram and then it's nailing the
content and nailing the content for us
has been different with each Creator
they're all obviously under the fitness
umbrella but they all represent a
different genre of training style but
really a different genre of white hot
user that care about different things if
you're somebody who's working out from
home and you want a Pilates influence
strength training routine that's really
different than somebody's looking for a
CrossFit type program in a commercial
gym they're just solving for completely
different different things meaning the
content that's going to work is not
going to be the same type of content and
so we had to work with each of our
coaches through this iteration period
because for the most part we're starting
from zero on figuring out what is the
niche and the content type that gets to
repeatable outcomes that's getting to
the right user that then becomes trilers
but it was all focused on the content to
start not on any sort of acquisition or
monetization it was all on can we create
great content that is providing value
and value in Tik Tok is you're either
teaching them or they're entertained and
that's it and if you nail those then
they're willing to learn more and
purchase from you but you've got to
understand the fundamentals of what
works for you the Creator and we just
learn a ton and so we have this
portfolio of coaches and we're learning
across them which is just 10 Xing our
speed because we're doing it so quickly
across multiple people but can't stress
it enough that versus Instagram or
anything else it is the creative that
you are winning or losing on right now
and it is creative for Tik Tok and
really understanding what that is can
make or break a strategy and if you're
not nailing that before spending a
dollar on paid marketing you're going to
give up pretty quickly and I've seen
that in a lot of friends and colleagues
and peers where I'm just like keep going
you have to keep going with this and you
have to learn it there's no Playbook yet
which means it's ugly and it just
requires blank sheet iteration and a lot
of detail oriented work to crack it part
of my question that you didn't answer
was on the CTA but I think it was very
formative that you didn't answer my
question on CTA because being successful
on Tik Tok it sounds like is a lot less
about the CTA and a lot more about
creating that valuable content I like
that framework too you're educating or
you're entertaining and maybe ideally
you're both educating and entertaining
at the same time but at some point they
do have to know that this is about an
app you do need to get them to take some
kind of action so then once you had
figured out some level of formulaic
production of valuable content how did
that become something that would
actually drive people to the app with
our coaches then it was iterating on
call to action how do I get people like
we're telling a very clear story in the
content itself and so you know that this
is the coach you know that this is
plotty strength you know that there's a
program and at the end we're iterating
on creative ways to get people into
their profil so click on the handle and
going down into the link that is their
ladder team landing page in their link
and bio on Tik Tok which is their only
link and that was just a game of
iteration like it just happened each
step it was nail the creative scale up
the viewers which is just creating great
creative and then figuring out how do I
get someone to do something else how do
I get somebody to go to my profile
follow me click the link download the
app and start a trial that was iteration
it was just maniacal focus at that
moment on that one thing it was
different across the coaches we
certainly learned where to start but it
was different can you share some
examples of what you're finding that did
work and maybe even some contrasting of
like this style CTA worked really well
for certain coaches but didn't work for
others but then this actually worked for
another coach yeah it's changed over
time like right now we're using a lot of
ctas and a lot of like time based
positioning where we start Monday or we
start November 6th and to start with us
my program is in my link in BIO and they
were not writing it in the text because
everyone's afraid that Tik Tok is
solving against that but putting it in
the video itself in font that's native
to Tik Tok using Tik Tok as the editing
tool so it just created ways of saying
we've got you you know what this is go
to my profile for XYZ go to my profile
to start Monday go to my profile to
start seeing results in the next four
weeks we're using start before New
Year's don't wait look good for the
holidays feel great don't think about
what to do every day we start Monday and
just telling the user where to go like
we learned that they will listen you
just have to be explicit and say there's
the next step here and the next step is
to go to my profile and click the link
and that's going to take you into the
app and into this incredible experience
where I'm your coach and you're going to
be receiving programming for me on a
daily basis that's awesome and from a
Tik Tock perspective
when you start putting money behind a
creative are you letting the algorithm
figure that out or are there specific
targeting or is there anything else
you're doing behind the scenes to help
the money you put behind it be more
effective there's a lot of hacky things
that we're doing in Tik Tok that we have
figured out just through having to
figure it out I'll give you one example
is everybody goes to our web quiz off a
Tik Tok ad every single person and
they're filling out those 15 questions
so again a million people have come
through that funnel and we're learning a
lot about who they are but we know their
Persona very very quickly based on their
questions and we spent a lot of time
getting that quiz dialed in to make sure
that people were actually filling it out
and not dropping off but the right user
was filling it out and we built an
entire Suite of software tools so that I
could iterate without an engineer and I
can move questions around and change
media without having to disrupt our road
map and that was a incredible product
that still exists that could be a
commercialized product that fuels all
this but for us what was really
impactful was using the answers on the
quiz as conversion events for Tik Tok so
Tik Tok isn't seeing basically anything
happening in the app they're learning
who our user is based on the answers
that they're giving us and then learning
off what a good user looks like off of
those conversions which are just
answering the question in the way that
we know it indicates a white how user
and that was really really important
because for us and we learned this with
the Facebook experience we had to be
really good and Scrappy at getting to
the right user and right now that's
somebody for the most part who's already
working out and the most expensive lead
to acquire is casual Fitness and
everybody in the world is advertising to
that person they're telling a story
about motivation and getting started and
they're talking about the size of the
workout library and how many coaches
they have and it's going to be fun all
of that is great but it's a really
expensive lead that doesn't really
convert very well in our product so if
I'm attracting a lot of folks with that
Persona they're not going to convert in
the economics are going to break so we
had to figure out how do we get dialed
in in terms of getting to the right user
and not getting to more casual Focus
folks folks who have never lifted a week
before never tried strength training
we've got big Visions on how to help
those people but at that moment in time
we didn't have a product for it and
using the quiz and mixtures of the
answers on the quiz is instantly got Tik
Tok dialed in and there was a week when
we were iterating because I'm reading
the answers right I had this spitting
out into amplitude and then into a
Google sheet so I could read the answers
coming in and I could see the profile of
these people and it was getting Tighter
and Tighter and Tighter and Tighter and
became very clear that we can get to the
right person efficiently it maybe is not
the obvious tactics that have been used
either on Tik Tok or other platforms but
this motion got it dialed in really
tight and that's still true today that's
a really solid funnel approach that I
hadn't heard anybody using before that
you're getting them out of Tik Tok onto
the web not into the app and so you have
a UTM in there so you're able to then
send very early feedback because they're
taking the quiz instantly so instead of
waiting for a conversion event that's
way down funnel and maybe in the app
where you can't get good tracking you're
actually getting that signal on the web
where they are where you can get that
feedback loop going which was very very
important for managing spend tiktock is
an unbelievable platform with 170
million Americans on it most days but
it's still an early stage company and
taking an established Facebook Playbook
even though that's been disrupted with
iOS 14 and the evolution attribution
there's still a Playbook and a lot of
people that have built big businesses in
the back of Facebook and that's just not
true yet on Tik Tok so it's a little bit
Wild Wild West so we've had conversation
with folks that will talk to us in the
conversation and say well you can't
raise your budget in any AD group AD set
by more than 30% a day and my question
would be like why what's the rationale
like oh ADV that's we learn on Facebook
and Performance Marketing we didn't hold
any of those as truce going into this
it's like all right if that's an
assumption then let's 2x or 3x the
budget in one day and see if it works
and these little moves would work so we
have people telling us one thing we're
trying another and it's working I spoke
at Tik toks one of their us all hands
last December and I was talking to all
their reps and really really smart
people but most of these reps came from
Facebook most of the folks in the
audience came from Facebook so they
would tell me and they were like we
don't recommend touching your as manager
and making budget changes you know
within the week and I'm like within the
week like I'm doing this three four five
times a day and it's make or break on it
working or not we've been able to use
the quiz because now I have a pixel on
every question and every combination of
question that I can see the cost metrics
in ads manager and I know what in the
money looks like for an answer to each
of our questions and then what happens
Downstream in the app I don't even have
to see what happens in the app I know
it's going to happen on the app just
based on these metrics and the reason
it's very hard right now with Tik Tok
we're fortunate it and that we're not
spending time or money anywhere else
we're unbelievably excited about Tik Tok
and we just don't have any reason to go
spend time elsewhere and what we learned
very early on in our Tik Tok iteration
was that most people wouldn't go down
this happy path of going from ad
clicking to the web quiz completing the
quiz downloading the app we would get a
bunch of people but it wasn't most we
learned that for every one person that
was answering the quiz three were going
directly to the App Store and there
taking a screenshot of the ad they were
sharing it with them themselves and I
talk to these people once they're in the
app I'm dming them like how'd you get
here I'm trying to extract and learn and
we learn that people were taking
screenshots of the app and then going to
the App Store and going down that path
which means I'm totally blind but we
studied with a lot of math and rigor the
correlation between those that were
coming through our happy path and what
was happening outside our happy path and
those ratios were very very tight every
time we had a new winning creative
anytime we added material spend or made
an unlock change and as manager I would
see the same Step Up in AB Store direct
trials and they would move in parallel
the charts moved exactly the same so it
gave me enough confidence even now to
know that if it's in the money and as
manager even though it doesn't reflect
everyone it reflects only those that
answered the quiz I can make all my
decisions off of that and I know what's
going to happen Downstream that's held
true even as we five six seven 8X budget
from a growth investment perspective so
you've already talked about it saying in
the money but how do you look at CA to
LTV and payback periods and how do you
spend into those creatives that are in
the money cocktail LTB at this stage I
think is Fairyland I think it's like
pitch deck metrics because the LTB in a
business that's been around for two or
three years or a business that just
started to invest in growth it's a guess
and you can extrapolate but it's not a
really good system to understand in my
mind your unit economics at that moment
and so we've anchored the entire team in
business to payback period which is just
way simpler cognitively to manage we
spent X cost Y and how fast does it take
based on what they paid and retention
does it cost to recoup that investment
and those inputs and the input levers
and output metrics those are
controllable by the team versus LTB
longterm like yeah we can guess but I
can't control that dayto day payback
period we understand the leverage and we
understand not even at the net faes but
the gross bases what's dropping down in
every dollar after I pay Facebook or
after I pay Apple and we pay Revenue cat
and any variable commissions what are we
earning versus what we spent and so it's
all payback period we're just constantly
talking to the team and educating on how
these things work so I almost never talk
about LTB to CAC unless you're talking
to some investor that has random rules
that they heard from another investor on
a podcast but I spend all this time
saying what we spend what we get when do
we get it back and how much burden is
that going to take to hit the gas and is
it changing or is it getting better and
how do we improve payback period and
that's been a much easier way to manage
and really have control of the levers
and payback period for us on Tik Tok has
gotten better as we've put a lot more
time and effort and money to work which
has been really exciting so we're
profitable on a uneconomic basis very
very quickly low single digit months and
it's been consistent and we've pulled on
that a little bit recently with annual
and we were mostly monthly for the first
three years for a couple different
reasons one we just didn't want the
complexity of dealing with this but we
wanted to have hard-earned retention
where we were learning what is the
correlation of behavior and membership
to month one retention month two
retention month three retention and
having that masked in annual is really
hard to use as a Guiding Light for the
team but if month one retention shits
the bed it's really clear what to Rally
the team around but if it's Mass it's
hard to understand what's really
happening you have to go really close to
the user to even have a first glimpse of
how all these things work together so we
started iterating very lightly on annual
and this was a few months ago knowing
that it would clearly have implications
on Payback period and we had a good
handle on retention and this was after a
whole bunch of product iteration so it
fell at the right time and for us it was
simplifying the checkout experience
making it really easy to understand the
offer after trial having just a simple
side by side between the monthly and the
annual and getting pricing right on the
annual and we had resources that we
studied and we studied dualingo at
nauseum who published a lot of
information on their iteration around
price boin we don't look to other
companies to guide what we do but we use
it as a starting point to put together a
thesis of something that we would try
and that was really really helpful for
us but we went from zero essentially
annual to 20% through that one move and
then we recently iterated again on price
point trying to understand what's the
clearing price where it actually is more
cash coming in because you're pulling in
more demand without giving too much up
on arpo or Mr and really deteriorating
the value per user and we played around
with price again and we're at about 30%
we'll spend more time on it down the
road but we're pretty excited by where
it's at and the impact that it's had on
our business and payback period so is
that 30% of conversions are now
selecting annual or 30% of Revenue is
now coming in annual 30% of new members
who get to the pay wall at the end of
trial so 30% of new people that passay
us are selecting annually check ah so
you're still 70% monthly on new members
on new MERS new members and then where
did you end up landing on pricing so are
you still at $30 a month for the core
product and then how did that translate
into your annual price we are the retail
is
$29.99 the first price point we tried
and we had done some campaign marketing
so we had data points to understand
what's the clearing price if it's not a
cash problem what's the price value
clearing price for people in their heads
and there are certain numbers that carry
weight that look like other subscription
apps whether it's $9.99 or 1499 19999
these are benchmarks in people's heads
so we had you know rough parameters and
our first iteration was taking it to
1999 and this last iteration was
$4.99 so $179 so it's 50% off the
monthly and we had learned there was
Magic on that 1499 through a whole bunch
of other price work and survey and
really understanding those that didn't
convert and we convert a high number of
triers to pay member but those that
didn't where is the price value you know
we're obviously using campaign levers
and different type of offers and 1499
was the clearing price at least
cognitively for a lot of folks that's
been an exciting move for us from an
annual take rate perspective yeah that's
still fascinating me so you're
converting 30% of new incoming users at
a 100
$80 upfront payment for the first year
correct wow but it's a 50% discount on
the $30 a month but 70% of people are
still choosing to pay month-to month
because it's not such a big upfront yeah
it's still high vers the in our content
we think is better than anywhere else
and it's Progressive and new every week
and it's being built by some of the best
coaches in string so the content itself
is definitely premium and content for us
isn't class base where you shoot a piece
of content front to back we shoot them
as individual movements in our gym
studio so when we launch a coach we'll
shoot a thousand individual movements
that are then used to construct workout
programming but on the monthly side I
think what was exciting for us one we
were able to ship the entire team to
growth because retention was really
strong very quickly it was clear this is
a retened product and very clearly we
were beating the benchmarks for our
industry but in consumer and you guys
Revenue cap put out an awesome doc that
Benchmark a whole bunch of companies
both just consumer subscription then
also by vertical and we were the top of
the pyramid for every one of the charts
on that page so retention was really
really compelling at the monthly basis
and like when we talk to companies that
had to go figure out annual they had to
go figure out annual to make the UN
economics on paid marketing work but
retention for us was strong enough where
we were profit itable on the user on an
un economic basis months after we
acquired wasn't one month wasn't two
months but months quick enough where you
could get to break even and see the path
very quickly and repeatably and so we
had air cover on retention so it hasn't
been a maker break for our business and
cash and new economics because retention
has been so strong now obviously annual
is super exciting it does lock people in
but it's cash upfront which for a
business at this stage is really really
helpful and sudden it lets us put it
back into growth and continuing to press
without just thinking about outside
Capital to do that so we've talked about
product a little bit but as you said
having great retention meaning having a
great product gave you air cover to
experiment and figure all of this out
what are the key things that you think
are driving that highly retentive
product in a space that is kind of
notorious for shedding users who to have
a New Year's resolution and stop working
out three weeks later yep there are a
lot of products that are just solving
for you to pay for the annual one time
and then maybe you use it maybe you
don't but the metric that we stare at
every day as a team is workout
completions and we study this maniacally
and we build product around workout
completions and understanding what are
the levers we have available to us that
really do move the needle on someone
completing the next workout or staying
consistent with us and our view and if
you read our app store reviews or some
of the awards we've won I think we have
the best product in the world in this
space in this genre for this user and it
was really built ground up as a consumer
retention oriented team we had to become
a growth user acquisition team but we're
a product Centric retention oriented
team we designed the experience really
for ourselves as the users but thinking
through what is the experience of
working with a personal trainer which is
by far the best experience that you
could have like we would agree with that
but it's prohibited from a price point
for most people it's not convenient from
a scheduling perspective it's awkward if
maybe you want to work with a different
coach and make a change it's just not
accessible but having someone tell you
what to do every day an unbelievable
amount of value in that experience so we
created this product really by
dissecting our own usage patterns but
also thinking through what are the
anchors that are the five-star 12st star
experience with working with a personal
trainer and those anchors are
programming you have somebody that tells
you what to do you don't have to think
there's no guesswork it's you wake up on
Monday put your shorts on press the
button and go so no thinking you can
just trust that it's designed by an
expert and it's the right thing based on
what you're solving for coaching you
have somebody there that's guiding you
and answering your questions and
accountability which You could argue is
the most important factor you have a
human being that's standing there with
you and you're going to go show up
because you don't want to piss off your
coach they standing there they're
waiting for you and it's an unbelievable
motivator and it's really a lot of the
value the workout programming is very
valuable but that accountability is
extremely valuable to showing up day in
and day out and we learn that very
clearly through this process on the
accountability side we designed from the
beginning social experiences that you
won't see in our website nobody buys or
tries a fitness app to make friends but
that's exactly what's happened we
created these experience where you're on
a team we call them teams these teams
are led by a coach this coach is a
superhero strength coach that represents
a specific programing modality that maps
to what we know about you and what
you're solving for these coaches are
really really good in front of the
camera they're unbelievable strength
coaches but we've created moments in the
app where they're talking to you and it
feels very personal and so there are all
these experiences that we've created
that leverage other people talking to
each other so you have somebody else
that's generally completing the same
workout as you on the same day though
asynchronously so it's relevant content
a relevant moment in time and you have
these creators or these coaches who are
there to basically help Drive early
activity in these chats they look like
slack groups but these things have taken
on a life of their own and they're
wildly popular and anytime you open our
app and go into one of these team chats
you'll hear somebody you'll read
somebody saying I wasn't going to work
out today and I came here and I saw you
guys talking about it and it motivated
me to go do it and this is every day we
see it and we have figured out from a
product growth perspective how to drive
people into chat earlier and we know
what that equals from a workout
completion perspective we know what it
equals from a consistency perspective
and so using elements like that really
studying dual lingo studying mobile
games all these things that create
addictive behavior but instead of
pointing them at ads and Screen Time
pointing them at workouts and using all
of these levers to keep you going so
we're just constantly thinking about how
do we take this experience and keep you
going and make sure that when you are
slipping or you need varability or
you're just tired and you need a kick
that we've got the right thing that's
happening inside of the app so all of
that was really intentionally designed I
think the last point on this experience
is this isn't a Content Library it's not
go in and choose a random 30 minute
workout it's prescriptive you're on a
team there are like tribal rituals
within these teams so much so that
people have pilgrimage to Austin to our
office to meet each other who met each
other in the app which is really
remarkable but this experience gets all
tied together in what we call strength
series and strength series are six week
programming cycles and we have six of
them in a year we call them the the
latter season and they're all tied to
the fitness calendar so in June July
we're shredding and all of our coaches
have that as a theme now what they're
doing how they're programming and their
Maneuvers and movements are different
but the theme is the same and it gives
us this lever where we're working
towards something at the member base and
you got to complete 20 workouts in that
string series to earn the badge and
people care about it but it also gives
us a window for new users to say this is
a great time to start like this is the
beginning so we get six High urgency
High intent moments that are mapped to
the calendar to get people in now we
have people starting every day and you
don't have to start in the beginning but
it creates a really clean narrative for
us to tell about why to start today so
those were all built ground up as a
product team trying to figure out what's
the ideal experience here where we're
keeping somebody for five years not five
months but like what has to be true to
keep somebody working out with us for
five years and that's been the guy
exting light for our team from a product
perspective for those of you listening
to this thinking I'm not a fitness app
or even if I am a fitness app I don't
have the coaches to replicate exactly
this experience that ladder is creating
I think there's so many lessons around
how Greg and his team are approaching
these things even if you can't replicate
onetoone the exact retention methods and
other things the idea behind it of
having that product Focus of looking at
dualingo style gamification and like how
do we bring people in what are those
core experiences that keep people
engaged it's just such an important way
to think and then as Greg said it's like
when you get those things dialed in you
have so much more flexibility in user
acquisition in having a highly retentive
user base you just have so much more
flexibility as a company and it's just
such a powerful tool that you can get to
leverage in every other part of the
business so where do things go from here
Greg how's your year been sounds like
things are going well yeah 2023 has been
transformative for ladder what feels
like counter everyone things that covid
was probably where we peaked we've
peaked after and haven't peaked yet but
have accelerated postco we built an
experience designed around a consumer
regardless of where they're working out
we can solve that at the program level
so in a mobile world it's as exciting as
it was when people were kind of Hostage
and thinking about new Solutions but
from a growth perspective I think you
nailed it we have a highly rended
product we have designed the team almost
in spinning flywheels within our team
where we can do a lot within a
15ers group but people aren't dependent
or bumping into each other and that's by
Design so all product and Engineering is
thinking about is retention and workout
completions that's all they're thinking
about every single day and we have a
really incredible creative team that
deeply part part of as the performance
marketer for ladder that has its own
motion and we have a team that manages
our programs and coaches that are
working with our coaches at the team
level staring at our data and trying to
figure out how do we improve the
experience and increase workout
completion so we're doing a lot with a
small group without having really
bureaucracy and politics and meetings
all the stuff that generally slows you
down that's been just a weapon and it's
helped us keep the team very lean but
this year we started the year with 9,000
paying subscribers and we'll beat
aggressive targ getting closed the year
north of 50,000 paying members and I
think we'll track towards something
that's as exciting next year and we've
got some really exciting Capital
Partners who have supported that Vision
that we've put out and we feel like
we're just getting started 500% growth
and not just 500% growth because I think
a lot of people like you were saying you
Orient everything around getting that
conversion whether people use the app or
not but 500% growth in a highly
retentive cohort is a really great
business that's how a subscription
business becomes a dualingo not the pump
and dump or hit a wall and the other
problems that we do see in the
subscription app industry it becomes
layers of a cake like the simple way I
explain it is we're spending X dollars
in ad and our burn is nowhere close to
what we're spending in ad because it's
compounding over time these layers are
being added on top not falling away very
quickly you're doing is playing catchup
to fill the Leaky bucket well I think
that's a great place to wrap up and
speaking of a small team doing Mighty
things you hiring or anything else you
want to share as we wrap up we are
always excited to talk to smart folks we
don't have any really critical missing
pieces today it doesn't mean that won't
change into next year so no clear open
roles but I would encourage everybody to
try the product everybody is skeptical
including every investor I first pitch
about another Fitness app but once they
get in there and you get through one or
two workouts you realize that this is
not like everything else and you can see
that how our members are talking about
us in the App Store so try the product
join lauder.com we'll ask you those
questions we'll give you a
recommendation on the right Plan and
there's no credit card for the trial so
absolutely no skin off your back to give
it a shot there was one last little
nugget in there if you're building
something that looks like every other
fitness app you probably shouldn't be
building a fitness app and raising money
yes and I think that just applies to any
app don't go build another app that
doesn't have clear differentiation and
that's what you're building a whole
business around is a product that really
is differentiated in the space and
that's why you've been able to grow and
scale and make things work the way you
have absolutely couldn't said it better
myself awesome thanks so much for
chatting today and look forward to
seeing louder's success in the future of
course thanks for having
me thanks so much for listening
if you have a minute please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player
you can also stop by chat. sub club.com
to join our private
[Music]
community